<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
 <generator>Neo900</generator>
 <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:42:25 +0200</lastBuildDate>
  <title>Neo900</title>
  <link>http://neo900.org/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[News about the Neo900 project.]]></description>
  <language>pl</language>
  <copyright>Sebastian Krzyszkowiak</copyright>
  <managingEditor>dos@dosowisko.net</managingEditor>
  <webMaster>dos@neo900.org</webMaster>
  <ttl>60</ttl>
  <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:42:25 +0200</pubDate>

  <item>
    <title>Neo900 Progress Update - May</title>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:42:25 +0200</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0011-progress-update-may]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
<p class="lead">Some of you may already have noticed that few days ago donations were suspended and Golden Delicious Computers announced stepping down and issuing refunds. What's going on? Is 
there something to worry about?</p>

<p><strong style="font-size: 1.5em">No!</strong> As strange as it may sound - the refunds seem to be <strong>the best way for the project to safely continue</strong>. And stepping down 
sometimes 
allows to take further 
steps 
forward.</p>

<p>In <a href="0010-progress-update-april">previous progress updates</a> we reported some organizational issues being worked on with lawyers and tax advisers. Despite of our earlier reports 
about 
success, it turned out that there are 
still 
important things to resolve. The hassle came mostly from the fact, that in the light of law, our structure looked completely different than it really was. Goldelico was supposed to take care of 
technical and logistic side of the project on behalf of Neo900 UG, but due to some mismatch between our intentions and resulting situation from legal point of view, it found itself at the position 
of entrepreneur. This wasn't the desired state of things for both sides and would cause problems sooner or later, so we tried to find a way to sort it all out. The most obvious solution - asking 
donors for permission and transferring the money to Neo900 UG - was rejected by tax advisers, despite of them suggesting it earlier (long story short: it could be possible with complete payments, 
but the VAT handling with the partial ones like we had caused the idea to collapse). During past few weeks some different ideas also got discussed, but there always was some part that someone 
wasn't happy with. After very long mail exchanging, GDC announced what we were all trying to avoid all that time.</p>

<p>GDC <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?p=1425501" target="_blank">announced</a> that it will step back from the project and refund the collected money (minus the already spent 
funds). 
Both sounds very serious and not really optimistic, just like our mood 
around 
that time. Fortunately, the sun started to show up from behind the rainy clouds pretty soon, first with Nikolaus clarifying that he's still interested in working on Neo900 and then with Joerg's 
idea of donors specifying Neo900 UG account as the destination account to refund the money by GDC.</p>

<p>That idea turned out to be ground breaking. GDC formally canceling the project and refunding the money seemed to resolve the issues with taxes. We consulted our lawyers and tax advisers once 
again 
and it turned out that <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?p=1426225" target="_blank">it's in fact the way to go</a>! We're canceling the donations and asking the donors to redo them, 
but 
with Neo900 UG instead of GDC now - and we're offering an option for direct 
transfer from GDC to Neo900 UG to avoid unnecessary hassle on your side and to avoid fees and currency conversion losses. Changing one small detail (transfer of order vs. refund + new 
donation) completely changed the game. Within the next few days all our donors will receive an e-mail with detailed instructions on what to do. <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?p=1426234" target="_blank">See details</a>.</p>

<p>To sum up, looks like "canceling the project" allowed us to finally fix the organizational structure issues and move everything forward. Legal world is indeed sometimes hard to follow...</p>

<p>OK, so what else? While fighting with the system and our mistakes from the past had eaten quite a lot of our time and resources, slowing down or even suspending the development at some point, 
there are still a few things worth noting in a progress update:</p>
<ul>
<li>
    Sebastian started <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=93210" target="_blank">his tests of PHS8 modem</a> on our first prototype board, resulting in <a 
href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FNSPEWvTJTc" target="_blank">this short video</a> showing "the 
family 
conversation" - that is, Neo900 (together with Debian PC it's 
connected to) and GTA04 (running SHR) calling each other and sending a text message using <a href="http://freesmartphone.org/" target="_blank">freesmartphone.org</a> middleware and SHR GUI apps.
<div style="margin: 10px 0">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FNSPEWvTJTc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</li>
<li>
    Also, the GPS/GLONASS engine has been tested with our Low-noise amplifier, layout and N900 antenna. Results: <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=93209" target="_blank">exciting and 
positive</a>! For example we seen a TTFF (warm) of ~10 seconds.
<div style="margin: 10px 0">
<a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=93209" target="_blank">
<img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/8497686/xgps2.png" width="560" />
</a>
</div>
</li>
<li>
    Sebastian also gave an OpenPhoenux related talk at <a href="http://piwo.informatyka.org/" target="_blank">P.I.W.O. Free Software event</a> in Poznań, Poland titled "Free Mobile - when Android 
is 
not enough". The slides in English are <a href="http://neo900.org/piwo/piwo.pdf" target="_blank">available here</a> 
and aside from covering some Openmoko/OpenPhoenux history and community projects, there is also an interesting part about privacy issues with cell phones and how Neo900 will deal with them, 
probably making Neo900 the safest phone you can get. We're also working on a more detailed paper on this topic - stay tuned!
<div style="margin: 10px 0">
<a href="http://neo900.org/piwo/piwo.pdf" target="_blank">
<img src="https://scontent-b-fra.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-frc3/t31.0-8/10257579_762890427076481_63679653399853938_o.jpg" width="560" />
</a>
</div>
</li>
<li>
    Nikolaus <a href="http://lists.goldelico.com/pipermail/gta04-owner/2014-May/005651.html" target="_blank">keeps working on 3.15 kernel for GTA04</a>, progressing further into <a 
href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/gta04-main/downloads/get/Device_Tree_Migration.pdf" target"_blank">the device tree 
migration</a>, which has interesting implication for our project: thanks to that it should be easy to 
create universal GTA04 images that work on every GTA04 based hardware - Neo900 included. This means that in many cases, GTA04 owners should be able to just take their SD cards and put them into 
Neo900, and vice versa, being able to boot exactly the same operating system as they used before!
</li>
<li>
    Speaking of GTA04, Sebastian recorded <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p1IM9Vd2_2s" target="_blank">a short video</a> showcasing <a href="http://replicant.us/" 
target="_blank">Replicant</a> 4.2.2 (FLOSS Android distribution) and <a 
href="http://shr-project.org/" target="_blank">SHR</a> 
running on GTA04, 
multibooting from the same SD card. Notice how smoothly 
Android works on this 800 MHz CPU without any 3D acceleration! Also note that this stuff should work on Neo900 just the same way.
<div style="margin: 10px 0">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/p1IM9Vd2_2s?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
<p>
And last, but definitely not least: say hello to our new, fourth team member, <strong>Werner Almesberger</strong>! Werner for now acts in an advisory role and helps with reviews, and may later 
play an 
active 
part 
in QA. He's an Openmoko veteran as well, recently involved in <a href="http://qi-hardware.com/" target="_blank">Qi Hardware</a> projects; author of <a 
href="http://en.qi-hardware.com/wiki/Ben_WPAN" target="_blank">Ben-WPAN</a> and <a href="https://gitorious.org/anelok/anelok" target="_blank">Anelok</a>, and all of you have used 
some of his 
contributions to Linux already.</p>

<p>As Friedrich Nietzsche famously said, <em>"what doesn't kill you makes you stronger"</em>. We feel that the Neo900 project is gathering strength after all the twists and turns it experienced. 
We're 
looking 
forward for the future with more optimism than ever, taking lessons from our past mistakes. Thank you for supporting us in this long and exciting journey!</p>]]>
                        </description>
                      </item>

  <item>
    <title>Neo900 Progress Update - April</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 23:09:18 +0200</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0010-progress-update-april]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p class="lead">Take part in documenting Neo900 compatibility with local carriers!</p>

<p>We are very often faced with questions like "which carrier will work with the Neo900?". Unfortunately, with so many different standards and bands used in different parts on the world, or even 
differences between various networks inside the same country, we are unable to provide comprehensive guide to Neo900 compatibility in every possible network on the world. Therefore we would like 
to kindly ask for your help!</p>

<p>On our <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/forumdisplay.php?f=57" target="_blank">Maemo Talk subforum</a> there's a <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=93095" target="_blank">Compatible 
carriers 
thread</a> 
where 
everyone can 
contribute and see the effect of compatibility 
evaluation done 
by 
others. At the moment of writing this note there's already comprehensive information about carrier support in USA and Poland. If you happen to know which bands are being used by carriers in your 
country, compare it to information from <a href="faq#networks">modem specification</a> and post your findings. Any help 
is 
appreciated!</p>

<p>In other news, the organizational structure around the project changed once again, rendering <a href="news-0009-progress-update-march">previous reports</a> about Neo900 UG already 
out of date. Fortunately, the new solution we had to come 
up 
with for money accounting reasons makes things actually easier - there will be no need for transferring the donated money to a new entity <a 
href="http://talk.maemo.org/showpost.php?p=1418094&postcount=1786" target="_blank">as announced previously</a>, so 
we 
won't bother our donors 
with asking for their permission to do so. As stated last time, <a href="faq#who">the people behind the project</a> remain unchanged - we just had to figure out the best solution to keep 
everything clear 
for 
everyone 
involved, especially tax office, which due to our non-standard way of raising funds turned out to be a bit more complicated than previously assumed.</p>


<p>What's next? While Joerg takes a well-deserved time off (or at least tries to - with workaholics like him you're never sure :)), Nikolaus is working on next PCB design for our prototypes, about 
which we'll write as soon as we get our hands on a package from factory. This new version will contain experimental circuits for charging (including first tests of promised hot battery swap), some 
parts of the audio system (amplifier, headset detection), more LEDs and it is planned to be able to connect it to some external device like BeagleBoard for testing the display interface 
(connector, 
signals etc). In addition there will already be the gesture recognizing touch decoder chip, accelerometer, gyroscope, compass and altimeter. We hope we get a good working solution for connecting 
the breakout board with the uSD reader and camera flash LEDs. Finally we have added circuits to monitor the modem - we will see how well they work - and the option to add a separate UART based GPS 
receiver so that we can disconnect the GPS antenna from the 3G module.</p>
<p>The status as of today is that the schematics are almost fixed for this version and fulfill most requirements we have set. Doing a good PCB layout simply takes time and only after building this 
intermediate step and testing it, we can start to finalize the first real and complete prototypes (which still will have some issues found only by heavy usage and testing).</p>
<p>For the software side, our sister project GTA04 has achieved good progress in a <a href="http://www.replicant.us" target="_blank">Replicant 4.2</a> (free Android distribution) port. It already 
works 
quite well and 
useable 
on a 800 MHz single core CPU 
with 
just 512 MB 
RAM and no(!) GPU acceleration support, so that we start to wonder what octacores with 2 GHz and 2 GB RAM are really required for. At least they are not required for the average user.</p>
<p>GTA04 is already stabilizing and completing a 3.15 kernel (currently -rc3). The most difficult changes are to get all drivers based on new device tree concept. All this experience will 
immediately 
be available for the Neo900 as well.</p>
<p>By the way, we're aware that the SSL certificate for shop.goldelico.com, where donating takes place, is currently expired, triggering security warnings from browsers - it should be fixed very 
soon 
(it is already ordered and paid, but did not arrive yet). We're sorry for the inconvenience.</p>

<p>Small teaser before the end: we're also working on new ways to keep you better informed about our progress and plans. Stay tuned!</p>]]>
                        </description>
                      </item>

  
  <item>
    <title>Neo900 Progress Update - March</title>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 23:12:10 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0009-progress-update-march]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p class="lead">The Neo900 project is still alive and steadily progressing.</p>

<p>Quite a lot of time has already passed since our last update. In case some of you felt unpleasant with already backed project not giving any sign of life - we're sorry that we exposed you to such feelings. Anyway, we're certainly not sorry to report that we're in fact still 
alive!</p>

<p>February was a pretty tough month for us. Most of the time, instead of doing what we love - that is designing the phone of our dreams - we had to get some organizational stuff sorted out. Lots of meetings with notaries and tax advisers were exhausting, but surely needed in 
order to ensure that our journey can be completed without unpleasant legal implications to anyone. This was one of the main reasons behind our limited activity, but luckily seems like we've got most of the important things sorted out.</p>

<p>The main result of all those efforts is the newly founded company, <strong>Neo900 UG</strong> (haftungsbeschraenkt), run by Joerg Reisenweber. The company takes the role of the head of this project and will hold its finances. Neo900 UG will continue the cooperation with 
Golden Delicious Computers GmbH&CO. KG on development of the Neo900 handsets, thus <a href="http://neo900.org/faq#who">the people behind the project</a> remain unchanged.</p>

<p>But it's not like we did nothing but talking with lawyers. We've been reporting some smaller stuff via <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=91142" target="_blank">our thread on Maemo Talk forums</a>. Let's sum it up!</p>

<ul>
<li>after some downtime thanks to service provider, the Neo900.org website has been moved to a new, dedicated server</li>

<li>remember the problematic display connectors? They are not problematic anymore - in a pretty tangible way:


<p style="margin: 20px 0">
<a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/various/DSC01847.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/various/DSC01847.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/various/DSC01849.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/various/DSC01849.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
</p>

<li>we managed to build a second mechanical evaluation prototype board to verify fixes made thanks to the first one and to find out what still has to be made.

<p style="margin: 20px 0">
<a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/DSC01862.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/DSC01862.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/DSC01856.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/DSC01856.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>

<a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/DSC01865.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/DSC01865.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/xDSC01853.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/xDSC01853.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<video controls src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0v2/pcb-a0v2.webm" width="267" height="150" autoplay loop style="vertical-align: middle"></video>
</p>
Note that the PCBs are thicker now than they will be in final device, resulting in larger gap under the display part (and the gap itself is going to be filled by the notorious spacer frame).
</li></ul>

<p>Lots of things are happening in stuff partially related to our project and it would be shame to not report the neater ones.</p>

<p>Have you heard about the <a href="http://www.pyra-handheld.com/" target="_blank">DragonBox Pyra</a> - the OMAP5 based <a href="http://openpandora.org/" target="_blank">OpenPandora</a> successor? Pyra, the "ultimate portable console", is expected to be released somewhere in 
2015.
Why are we promoting it here? Aside of sharing the same message about hardware openness, the OpenPhoenux community had already helped to make production of OpenPandora possible when its future was uncertain due to production problems; but now we're collaborating even closer. Dr. 
H. Nikolaus Schaller, CEO of Golden Delicious Computers and one of the heads behind the Neo900 project, is also working on the new Pandora. The close collaboration between our projects can lower the prices thanks to component re-use. We're also looking forward to the knowledge 
gained by working on OMAP5 design, which may be helpful for possible future Neo900 successors and/or update modules. At the end of February, on <a href="http://www.embedded-world.de/en/" target="_blank">embedded world 2014</a> in Nürnberg there has been an informal meeting of 
some CEOs: Nikolaus (Golden Delicious Computers GmbH&CO. KG), Joerg (Neo900 UG (haftungsbeschraenkt)), Michael Mrozek (OpenPandora GmbH) and Lukas Märdian (working for GDC on <a href="http://replicant.us/" target="_blank">Replicant</a>) and opportunities of closer collaboration 
and 
synergies got discussed. So... say hello to <a 
href="http://www.pyra-handheld.com/" target="_blank">the Pyra</a>!</p>

<p>Few days ago the <a href="http://freesmartphone.org" target="_blank">freesmartphone.org</a> project has moved its defunct for some time mailing lists to <a href="http://lists.goldelico.com/mailman/listinfo/fso">OpenPhoenux servers</a>, and together with that move Dr. Michael 
Lauer, one of the FSO fathers and member of the original team of Openmoko engineers, announced his return to the project after dropping out about 3 years ago when his daughter was born. Together with the announcement, he introduced his <a 
href="http://lists.goldelico.com/pipermail/fso/2014-March/000002.html" target="_blank">FSO revitalizing plan</a>. The fate of FSO is crucial for some of the software projects that we hope to see working on Neo900, possibly including the Maemo Fremantle port, so we're crossing 
our fingers for its success!</p>

<p>There's also a hot news circulating the media right now about a <a href="http://redmine.replicant.us/projects/replicant/wiki/SamsungGalaxyBackdoor" target="_blank">possible backdoor in Android modem libraries</a> on some Samsung phones, revealed by <a 
href="http://replicant.us/" target="_blank">Replicant</a> developers one 
month ago. Revelations like that always shed some light on how we perceive the usage of closed, proprietary software on our devices. In fact, most of modern devices don't even need such backdoor to be able to spy on users, as their modems are directly connected to the main RAM, 
allowing it to read and manipulate anything that runs on the main CPU. While we sadly cannot provide fully free modem due to both lack of resources and problems with legislation effectively rendering firmware-modified modem illegal to use under most jurisdictions, we're glad to 
tell that Neo900 is from the very beginning being designed in a way that makes possible backdoors like the one found on Samsung phones practically impossible to occur - which is important due to fact that we're going to use a third party modem module in which we don't have any 
control over the internals like its firmware. We won't allow the modem to access any data that's not supposed to be available to it and all of our hardware choices are always made with the 
ability to use free software drivers in mind. Our phones are not supposed to be the tools used by others to spy on us.</p>

<p>Also, there's a <a href="http://lists.goldelico.com/pipermail/community/2014-March/000866.html" target="_blank">good progress being made</a> on Replicant port for GTA04 and the upstream 
developers have recently <a 
href="http://lists.goldelico.com/pipermail/gta04-owner/2014-February/005377.html" target="_blank">resumed their efforts</a> to get GTA04 officially supported by this free Android 
implementation. Most of this work should be pretty much reusable on Neo900 as well, and 
Replicant developers have already expressed their initial interest for Neo900 port. Let's hope that all those efforts, together with <a href="http://freesmartphone.org/" target="_blank">freesmartphone.org</a> stack and Fremantle port getting <a 
href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?p=1410991#post1410991" target="_blank">more and 
more 
closed blobs 
replaced</a> 
by 
free equivalents, will 
provide the solid base for the 
free software operating systems for mobile phones and the Neo900 itself will start the new branch of freedom and privacy respecting mobile devices - based on what was started few years ago by Openmoko and is now proudly continued by the OpenPhoenux community.</p>

<p>All of that was about what was done - but what's next?</p>

<p>We're looking forward to getting the next prototype done by the end of the month, and as this work is being done in parallel to the prototype of the DragonBox Pyra, we'll be already able to 
share some interesting components with that project. There are also discussions 
happening internally right now about the implementation details and component choosing for our modem sandboxing and monitoring solution, robust battery charging, RGB LEDs controllers, battery hotswap support, nice WLAN module etc.</p>

<p>So to sum everything up: if someone hoped to see our project turning into forgotten vaporware - sorry to disappoint you! We're on an exciting journey to finally get a really hacker-friendly phone and we're not gonna abort our mission that easily! :)</p>

<p><em>PS. Happy Pi Day!</em></p>]]>
                        </description>
                      </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Neo900 Progress Update - January</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 18:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0008-progress-update-january]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p class="lead">With the biggest obstacles now overcome, we are again gaining speed to reach the next goal.</p>

<p>A long time has already passed since the last update. Since holidays, the greatest nightmare of the project to date - <a href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/536/">the 500246471 Molex display connector</a> - has been finally dealt with, giving us a few possible sources for the component. We would like to say thank you to all people who helped with this difficult subject, once again proving the awesomeness of this community!</p>

<p>The first tests made with 40-pin variant of the connector (we need 64-pin one) assured us that our identification is correct and we may really buy it without the risk of component mismatch.</p>

<p style="margin: 20px 0">
<a href="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01828.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01828.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<a href="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01830.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01830.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<a href="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01831.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01831.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<a href="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01832.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01832.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
<a href="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01833.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
<img src="http://maemo.cloud-7.de/Neo900/media/pic+vid/DSC01833.jpeg" width="200" />
</a>
</p>


<p>We have ordered a first quantity of those connectors based on our current <a href="http://neo900.org/#donate">"preorder" counter</a>, experience, guessing and calculations. However, when the cost per component goes higher we won't be able to guess anymore. At that moment - so it happens before regular orders open up - the amount of orderable devices will be frozen, determined by the number of preorders we received. Thankfully this is something we managed to avoid this time.</p>

<p>We have also received next PCBs with most of <a href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/518/">the issues found on earlier ones</a> already fixed, making further progress in mechanical evaluation of our board in connection to the original N900 case.</p>

<p>On the other side, we started to <a href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/546/">collect possible options for WiFi/BT/FM/NFC module</a> to be used in Neo900. We are also looking for the feedback from community in order to find out which module would be the most appreciated by our users. Don't hesitate to <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?p=1404178#post1404178">share your thoughts</a> on <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/forumdisplay.php?f=57">our new subforum</a>!</p>

<p>While dealing with big issues, small but fancy details are not forgotten - for instance, we plan to bring <a href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/541/">RGB keyboard illumination</a> to Neo900 using three LP5523 controllers (which by the way is a <a href="https://pavelmachek.livejournal.com/120188.html">pretty hackable beast</a>), enabling unusual expression abilities for the light under the keys. We also keep evaluating new possibilities, like <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?p=1405134#post1405134">decent video output</a> (VGA/HDMI/SlimPort), <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?p=1405843#post1405843">DVB-T tuner and SDR receiver, pager</a> etc. Obviously we cannot promise any of those functionalities right now, but we want to keep an eye on what's possible and feasible for the project, so if some highly desirable feature can make it into the device without adding big overhead for time of delivery and/or costs, we will be happy to integrate it into your devices, thus 
produce more of them for even better price while having more features. Your insight is welcome and highly appreciated in <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=91142">our forum thread</a>!</p>

<p><a href="https://shop.goldelico.com/wiki.php?page=Neo900" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg" style="margin: 20px 0;">Claim your device now!</a></p>]]>
                        </description>
                      </item>

  <item>
    <title>Happy Holidays!</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 15:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0007-happy-holidays]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p class="lead">The fundraiser reaches 25% of current goal and the hardware evaluation
is in progress.</p>

<p>While the early device as shown in <a href="http://neo900.org/news-0006-progress-update">the last progress update</a> is being
carefully checked by Joerg and Nikolaus ordered new "upper" PCBs
expected to come in early January, our efforts will obviously slow
down a bit during the next days due to holidays - and while we're at
it, we would like to wish all of you a Merry Christmas and a Happy New
Year!</p>

<p>The device counter on <a href="http://neo900.org/#donate">our website</a> has reached 250, which is a quarter
of the current goal. While we're above the minimal threshold of 200
(thanks for your support!), we still need as much as we can to make
part sourcing easier, better components possible and the unit price
lower. Maybe the Neo900 pre-order voucher may work as a great Xmas
gift for someone close? :)</p>

<p>We're also working on making our website better. We want to bring more
life into it by adding blog section to make our communication with you
easier and more frequent, and to prepare the site to contain more and
more additional content appearing during the development, like the
article about user privacy in Neo900 which is supposed to be published
soon.</p>

<p>We're thrilled to step into the year 2014 and happy to be able to
bring this project forward, making the final production closer and
closer.</p>

<p>See you next year!</p>]]>
                        </description>
                      </item>

  
  <item>
    <title>Neo900 Progress Update - December</title>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 14:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0006-progress-update]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p class="lead">Time for some news about what's going on in the project - phase V reached, dual-touch support, new test boards, discussions about user privacy and more!</p>
      
      <h4>Funding campaign</h4>
      
      <p>A few hours after publishing <a href="http://neo900.org/news-0005-phase-i-results-ohsw-showcase">our last update</a>, the counter on the website
        reached the magic number - 200, causing the transition <a target="_blank" href="http://neo900.org/#donate">from phase IV
          to phase V</a>! Thank you once again! This means that the current goal is
        to reach at least 1&nbsp;000 customers wanting to ensure that they'll get
        the device from first production batch. The closer we are to reaching it, the
        easier are some components to get (like <a target="_blank" href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/516/">1 GB RAM chip, with minimum
          order quantity of 1&nbsp;000 units</a>) and the cheaper every single device will become. Right
        now we're at about 235 devices. Please spread the word about Neo900 -
        everyone benefits from that counter reaching a high value!</p>
      
      <h4>New features</h4>
      
      <p>In other news, we're happy to announce that Neo900 hardware is <a target="_blank" href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/527/">going
          to support dual-touch gestures</a> like rotating and pinching, without
        replacing the original, resistive screen from N900! Though we originally planned to see if we can implement this principle with
        discrete components, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.freescale.com/webapp/sps/site/prod_summary.jsp?code=CRTOUCH&nodeId=0112698268">the chip</a> that has been suggested by user wentknweqt_ on IRC allowed us to greatly simplify our design. Thanks! You can read more about how it works in <a target="_blank" href="http://talk.maemo.org/showpost.php?p=1393889&postcount=1473">Joerg's TMO post</a>.</p>
      
      <h4>News from our R&D department</h4>
      
      <p>We've made some progress on <a target="_blank" href="http://download.goldelico.com/neo900/images/images.php#2013:12:10">our proto-boards</a>. We have finalized one
        PHS8-P based set of boards, featuring the LEDs to test keyboard
        illumination. We will also use the boards to run further tests - voice calls (with analog audio for initial testing), GPS and keyboard itself. Our next step will be to do a redesign of the boards based on <a target="_blank" href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/518/">all
          experiences</a> (e.g. moving some holes and components by 0.1 - 0.5 mm)
        and to add more functionality for the next round of engineering tests.
        We expect to have something more to test in January.</p>
      
      <p style="margin: 20px 0">
        <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01804.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
          <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/thumbnails/DSC01804.JPG" width="200" />
          </a>
          <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01805.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
            <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/thumbnails/DSC01805.JPG" width="200" />
            </a>
            <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01800.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
              <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/thumbnails/DSC01800.JPG" width="200" />
              </a>
            </p>
            
            <h4 id="more">Issues and a request for help</h4>
            
            <p>Side by side with nice successes there also always come some inevitable problems, always
              willing to arrive at least expected places (Murphy's Law, §42). Our biggest headache
              right now is <a target="_blank" href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/issues/536/">Molex 5000246471 connector</a> (used to connect the display
              part) which is officially obsolete since Feb 2013. We're also looking
              for complete N900s in good quality (though possibly with broken mainboard) as well for as sources for spare parts. We'd
              like to kindly ask our community for a little bit of help there -
              especially for sourcing the display connector. If you know some way to
              help, please <a href="contact">contact us</a>!</p>
            
            <h4>Privacy and FSF approval</h4>
            
            <p>In the past few days we've seen many questions from users concerned about
              their privacy when using the Neo900, coming also from FSF-related people
              and even Mr. Richard Stallman himself. The Neo900 is very likely going to be the
              best phone you can find to take care about protecting your privacy, but we'd like to clarify that
              while we share the spirit behind Free Software Foundation and their consumer
              privacy concerns, and our design takes into consideration majority of
              their recommendations, there are some differences in our approach where we disagree with FSF and
              we believe that in fact our concept is better for user privacy and freedom than
              what FSF suggests.</p>
            
            <p>We are going to use Neo900 too and we are as concerned about our
              own privacy as many of our users are about theirs. Therefore, in next few days
              we're going to publish a comprehensive article about our views on this
              topic, clarifying in detail why exactly our views differ from FSF
              point of view and what we are going to offer instead - information
              that's currently spread across various IRC logs, e-mails and forum posts. Stay
              tuned!</p>
            
            <h4>GTA04A5 campaign</h4>
            
            <p>Last but not least: our sister project, <a target="_blank" href="http://gta04.org/">GTA04</a>, started <a target="_blank" href="http://shop.goldelico.com/wiki.php?page=GTA04A5">the fundraiser</a>
              for producing new revision of this Openmoko Neo Freerunner replacement
              board - <a target="_blank" href="http://shop.goldelico.com/wiki.php?page=GTA04A5">GTA04A5</a>, enhancing some stuff and fixing a few minor issues
              found in earlier revisions. The campaign has already collected 1&nbsp;930
              EUR for 16 devices and is now heading for 5&nbsp;000 EUR, which would
              translate into 50 units.
              If you're interested in upgrading your Freerunner or getting a whole
              device, <a target="_blank" href="http://shop.goldelico.com/wiki.php?page=GTA04A5">pre-order now</a>! You can also order used Neo Freerunner now and get a rebate on GTA04 when it's ready. The success of GTA04 campaign
              will also positively influence the Neo900 project, as both boards
              share the majority of their components.</p>
            
            <p>Thank you for tremendous support and interest we've received so far
              and see you in next update!</p>]]>
                        </description>
                      </item>
                      
  
  <item>
    <title>Phase I results - OHSW showcase</title>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0005-phase-i-results-ohsw-showcase]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p class="lead">The Neo900 project managed to reach the first stage of development and presented the results at the OpenPhoenux Hard- and Software Workshop in Munich.</p>
      
      <p>It's time for a new update about what's going on in the project and we're happy to say that we've got a lot of things to report on since <a href="http://neo900.org/news-0004-progress-update">the last one</a>!</p>
      
      <p>For starters, we've received first PCBs and samples (modem, SIM and SD holders etc.) for mechanical evaluation. </p>
      
      <p style="margin: 20px 0">
        <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01780.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
          <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01780.jpeg" width="200" />
          </a>
          <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01783.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
            <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/DSC01783.JPG" width="200" />
            </a>
            <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01784.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
              <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/DSC01784.JPG" width="200" />
              </a>
            </p>
            
            <p>The results were mostly positive - PCBs fit into the N900 case - and showed few small details that need to be fixed, like camera socket and SD holder placement or some shape measurements being slightly off. This kind of issues is exactly what we were supposed to detect and fix thanks to this board.</p>
            
            <p style="margin: 20px 0">
              <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01787.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
                <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/DSC01787.JPG" width="200" />
                </a>
                <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01790.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
                  <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/DSC01790.JPG" width="200" />
                  </a>
                  <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01791.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
                    <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/DSC01791.JPG" width="200" />
                    </a>
                  </p>
                  
                  <p>Actually, that's all from what we initially planned for this update - but in fact, there's more! While great amount of our attention is directed at component sourcing matters, we already wanted to make something that... does something. The GTA04b7v0 boards, meant for mechanical evaluation, have been also used to electrically evaluate the board with the modem already soldered on it, testing the modem footprint as well as our soldering process which can be tricky for such a huge component.</p>
                  
                  <p style="margin: 20px 0">
                    <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01797.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
                      <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01797.jpeg" width="200" />
                      </a>
                      <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01798.jpeg" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
                        <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01798.jpeg" width="200" />
                        </a>
                        <a href="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/DSC01793.JPG" rel="lightbox" data-lightbox="p1">
                          <img src="http://neo900.org/photos/neo900/pcb-a0/thumbnails/DSC01793.JPG" width="200" />
                          </a>
                        </p>
                        
                        <p>How it turned out? See it by yourself on <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://neo900.org/ohsw2013">the recording</a></strong> from <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://neo900.org/ohsw2013/slides">Neo900 talk</a></strong> on <a target="_blank" href="http://ohsw.org/">OHSW 2013</a> held by Dr. H. Nikolaus Schaller!</p>
                        
                        <p style="margin: 20px 0">
                          
                          <a target="_blank" href="http://neo900.org/ohsw2013" style="position: relative; display:inline-block; width: 400px">
                            <img src="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/VWPmXxq1MdQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="100%" />
                            <img src="http://static.neo900.org/youtube.png" style="position: absolute; top:50%; left:50%; margin-left:-60px; margin-top:-45px;" />
                            </a>
                          </p>
                          
                          <p>In other news, right now we're at 188 devices in the fundraiser, which means that we're getting close to reaching phase 4! Can we go even further and reach 1000 devices (phase 5), or maybe 1000 devices per month (phase 6), significantly lowering the price of the final device? It all depends on you - it's not too late to jump in!</p>
                          
                          <p>Our website is also being constantly updated. This time we once again augmented <a href="http://neo900.org/faq">our FAQ</a> with the answers to some popular questions and added more details to already existing ones.</p>
                          
                          <p>We're happy to be able to show some working hardware just a month after the start and we're thrilled to continue our efforts to bring you the complete, finished Neo900 phones. Stay tuned for more updates!</p>]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  
  
  <item>
    <title>Neo900 Progress Update - November</title>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 02:34:20 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0004-progress-update]]></link>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[<p class="lead">After unexpectedly successful launch of our fundraiser, the project is
        progressing well.</p>
      
      <p>Thanks to amazing support from our community we're already
        <a href="http://neo900.org/news-0003-we-ve-reached-our-goal">past the first three phases of our fundraiser</a>, reaching our first,
        monetary goal. Thank you! However, now we need to ensure that we'll be
        able to sell at least 200 devices, as that's the amount we've been
        using in our price calculations and feasibility evaluation. We assume
        that all donors pledging 100 € or more will want to use their rebate
        on finished device, so we count them as our customers. At this moment
        we only need 50 more potential Neo900 owners to go!</p>
      
      <p>Of course the fundraiser is not the only thing happening in the
        project. The fundraiser kept us so busy that we failed to publish
        a new newsletter more timely, even though there're lots of stuff to
        report on. We've already designed <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tXlQLMzFqcc">first prototype PCB</a> and <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showpost.php?p=1387162&postcount=1259">ordered
          it</a>, hoping to demonstrate the modem's functions (data, voice, GPS) and mechanical integration into the N900 case
        on first real hardware coming from this project at <a href="http://ohsw.org/">Open Hard- and
          Software Workshop</a> in Garching (Munich), Germany, taking place
        30. Nov - 1. Dec 2013. For those of you who cannot appear there
        in person we're going to provide YouTube live stream from the event.
        Stay tuned!</p>
      
      <p>Some people were wondering how the battery hotswap feature is going to
        look like. Joerg has prepared <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ta7Mh9a_y8">a short video clip</a> showing amazingly
        easy battery replacement procedure. The Neo900 is going to be designed
        in such a way that replacing battery will be possible without turning
        it off, even without attaching external power from USB!</p>
      
      <p>Our web page is constantly getting some layout and content
        improvements. One of the most frequently asked questions was about the
        openness and freedom of the device and how we're going to reach our
        goals regarding user privacy with blackbox modem module. The answers
        are now available at <a href="http://neo900.org/faq#floss">our FAQ page</a>.</p>
      
      <p>We would also like to announce that <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showpost.php?p=1387111&postcount=1256">we plan to publish EAGLE
          project files</a>, allowing everyone with enough time, skills and money
        to improve on our work and do their own hardware modifications on the
        mainboards. This would make Neo900 the only phone available on the
        market with such degree of openness!</p>
      
      <p>Our community is also progressing with their tasks - <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=91308">the Fremantle
          Porting Task Force project</a> recently managed to boot Maemo 5 with
        recent version of Linux kernel (3.12) and came up with reverse
        engineered version of MCE daemon, responsible for controlling some
        peripherals of N900, bringing the project few steps closer to provide
        working Fremantle system on platforms like Neo900.</p>
      
      <p>Thanks for following this project and stay tuned for more!</p>]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  
  
  <item>
    <title>We've reached our goal!</title>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 14:42:20 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0003-we-ve-reached-our-goal]]></link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p class="lead">Our fundraiser campaign turned out to be big success, collecting 25 000 € in less than a week!</p>
        
        <p>Thanks to around hundred of donors, we have finally reached our last goal in the fundraiser. That means that we should be able to make the design production ready and prepare to the shipping of around 200 devices!</p>
        
        <p>We were hoping to be able to reach that goal at the end of the year, but it turned out that the community is much more excited about our project than we initially thought! That's a big responsibility that lies on our shoulders and we promise to do anything possible to not disappoint any of you.</p>
        
        <p>However, it doesn't mean the end of the fundraiser. Although we're not specifying any next phase to reach, the donations are still open and the rewards still apply. Why? We decided to follow the momentum and give any late-commers the chance to get the rebate. If it turns out that our goal of 200 devices is too low for the demand, we'll be able to find out how many devices should we produce and request the components in adequate amounts. In layman's terms - the more people donate and want to use their rebate for the device, the cheaper it becomes. For everyone.</p>
        
        <p>Additional funds may also be used for research about providing features or stuff like modular design, upgrades of parts initially supposed to be re-used etc. If we for some reason won't be able to use collected money, it will be refunded.</p>
        
        <p>Thanks to reaching our goal this fast, we should be able to showcase the project on <a href="http://ohsw.org/">OpenPhoenux-Hard-Software-Workshop 2013</a> which takes place in Munich at the end of November. Feel invited!</p>
        
        <p>Last but not least, we would like to say <strong>thank you</strong> once again to everyone who supported or are still going to support our project. It wouldn't be possible without your help!</p>
        
        <p>Let the phoenux fly!</p>]]>
      </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Neo900 fundraiser past the phrase II, 5 000 € to go</title>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 21:22:20 +0100</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0002-fundraiser-past-the-phrase-ii-5-000-to-go]]></link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p class="lead">We've already reached two out of three milestones in our fundraiser campaign!</p>
          
          
          
          <p>Thanks to amazing support from people interested in the project, the <a href="http://neo900.org/#donate">progress bar</a> has reached the level of <strong>15 000 €</strong> in <strong>less than three days</strong> since the start of the campaign. This means we now expect that we should be able to create the schematics, identify componends and do initial mechanical PCB design (phrase I) as well as build around five prototypes with basic functionality, such as CPU, display, keyboard and UMTS working (phrase II).</p>
          
          <p>We would like to thank all the people who decided that our project follows their interests and donated their money to keep it running. Especially we want to thank everyone who donated less than 100 €, supporting us with anything they could without expecting anything in return. Worth mentioning are also the donors who generously pledged 1 500 € or more, already giving a new home to <strong>three early prototypes</strong>.</p>
          
          <p style="font-size: 1.5em; text-align: center">Thank you!</p>
          
          <p>However, our journey is <strong>not over yet</strong>. We still need to collect 5 000 € in order to reach our primary goal and <strong>make the design production ready</strong>. Please <a href="https://shop.goldelico.com/wiki.php?page=Neo900">keep it rolling</a>!</p>
          
          <p>As a sidenote, some people reported problems with rejected credit card transactions or missing "destination country". Please remember that while every donation is appreciated, some automatic creditibility systems may incorrectly mark your donation attempt as a fraud. Please <a href="http://talk.maemo.org/showpost.php?p=1383775&postcount=1026">follow the instructions</a> in case of any problems and don't try to workaround them by yourself - we'll try to assist you in the process and find individual solutions.</p>
          
<p>Once again, thank you for your support. Hopefully you'll let us make the next announcement very soon! :)</p>]]>
   </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Neo900 fundraising campain has started!</title>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 21:18:09 +0200</pubDate>
    <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org/news-0001-fundraising-campain-has-started]]></link>
     <description><![CDATA[ <p class="lead">We're thrilled to announce that our fundraising campain with a goal of <strong>25 000 €</strong> has just started!</p>
 
 <p>The <span class="neo900">Neo900</span> project hasn't been forgotten. We're working very hard in order to make our dream come true, and we still keep in mind our promises
 about not working behind the walls. To be able to properly develop bug-free devices, we first need to build prototypes, which are quite expensive. That's why we have launched
 <a href="https://shop.goldelico.com/wiki.php?page=Neo900">
   <strong>a fundraiser</strong> with a goal of <strong>25k EUR</strong>
 </a>.</p>
 
 <p>The fundraiser will actually provide triple purpose, as <strong>your donated money will also serve as a discount on the final device price</strong> and it will give us a feedback about number of interested customers, so we can bring the project forward. The further development will start as soon as the minimal amount needed to proceed arrive.</p>
 
 <p>The level of funding will be available to see in "real time" on our <a href="http://neo900.org/">main page</a>.</p>
 
 <p>To make your decision better justified, we've been also preparing a brochure called <strong><a href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/neo900/downloads/get/neo900-feasibility.pdf">feasibility study</a></strong>, containing exactly what we plan to do and what we consider easy, difficult, or desirable but probably impossible. This way we want to allow anyone interested in the project
   to make up their own opinion if the project is really what they want and expect.</p>

<p>We're excited to bring this project forward. Thank you for your support!</p>]]>
</description>
   </item>
  <item>
     <title>Introducing Neo900</title>
     <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 01:42:44 +0200</pubDate>
     <link><![CDATA[http://neo900.org]]></link>
     <description><![CDATA[
      <div class="row featurette">
        <div class="col-md-7">
          <h2 class="featurette-heading">Smooth upgrade. <span class="text-muted">Finally!</span></h2>
          <p class="lead">
            The <strong class="neo900">Neo900</strong> project aims to provide a Fremantle (<a href="http://maemo.org/intro/">Maemo&trade;</a> 5) compatible successor of N900, with <strong>faster CPU</strong>, <strong>more RAM</strong> and <strong>LTE modem</strong>,
              basing efforts on an <strong>already existing</strong>, mature and stable free platform - the&nbsp;<a href="http://openphoenux.org">OpenPhoenux</a> <a href="http://gta04.org"><strong>GTA04</strong></a>.
          
          <p>We'll provide both complete, <strong>ready to use devices</strong> in N900 case, and <strong>motherboard replacements</strong> for your current device.
             <span class="neo900">Neo900</span> will also support all operating systems available for GTA04 (<a href="http://qtmoko.sourceforge.net/">QtMoko</a>, <a href="http://shr-project.org/">SHR</a>, <a href="http://debian.org/">Debian&trade;</a>, <a href="http://replicant.us/">Replicant</a>, ...)
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-5">
          <img style="margin-top: 30px" src="http://neo900.org/img/neo900.jpg" class="featurette-image img-responsive" alt="Neo900">
        </div>
      </div>
      
      <!-- Example row of columns -->
      <div class="row">
        <div class="col-lg-4">
          <h2>Choice.</h2>
          <p>
          <span class="neo900">Neo900</span> comes with <strong>great diversity</strong> of available operating systems. Want to use <a href="http://qtmoko.sourceforge.net/">QtMoko</a>? <a href="http://shr-project.org/">SHR</a>? <a href="http://debian.org/">Debian&trade;</a>? <a href="http://android.com/">Android&trade;</a> (<a href="http://replicant.us/">Replicant</a>, <a href="http://forum.nitdroid.com/">NITdroid</a>)? No problem, switch them in few minutes!
          Maybe you're interested in porting <strong>Ubuntu&trade;</strong>, <strong>Firefox OS&trade;</strong> or something else? Creating your own system? You're <em>more than welcome</em>!
          </p>
<!--          <p><a class="btn btn-default" href="#">View details &raquo;</a></p> -->
        </div>
        <div class="col-lg-4">
          <h2>Openness.</h2>
          <p>There's <strong>no other</strong> mobile phone available which offers such a degree of openness like <span class="neo900">Neo900</span> does. <strong>No <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_blob">binary blobs</a></strong> are needed to make it usable. 
          Also, <a href="http://projects.goldelico.com/p/gta04-main/page/Manual/">full documentation and schematics</a> can take tinkering with your phone to the next level. Use <strong>expansion interfaces</strong> for your own mods and reworks. Why limit your thoughts to the software?
          </p>
       </div>
        <div class="col-lg-4">
          <h2>Support.</h2>
          <p>Tired of big vendors dropping support for their old devices when the new model becomes available? <span class="neo900">Neo900</span> is a <strong>community-based project</strong>, just like <a href="http://wiki.maemo.org/Community_SSU">Maemo CSSU</a>, and <a href="http://openphoenux.org/">OpenPhoenux</a> roots are based on a professional <a href="http://openmoko.org/">Openmoko</a> background.
          You can expect new updates even <strong>years after release</strong>.
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>


      <div class="row featurette">
        <div class="col-md-5">
          <img src="http://neo900.org/img/neo900-avatar.jpg" style="margin-top: 10px; margin-bottom: 50px" class="featurette-image img-responsive" alt="Neo900">
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-7">
          <h2 class="featurette-heading">Hacker friendly. <span class="text-muted">Without limits!</span></h2>
          <p class="lead">

We're commited to provide <strong>the best hacking experience</strong> possible.
Even if we have no idea how to make use of some feature, <strong>you</strong> might have one and we won't stop you from <strong>implementing it</strong>.</p>
<p>Our dream is to get <strong>all your crazy needs</strong> covered. You can expect <strong>dual SIM support</strong>, combined <strong>GPS and GLONASS</strong> navigation system, stereo <strong>line-in</strong> and additional <strong>connection pads</strong> for your own or third party hardware - and those are just the biggest ones.</p>

          <h2 class="featurette-heading">Privacy control. <span class="text-muted">In your hands.</span></h2>

<p class="lead">Reliable GSM and GPS shutdown from the software.<br/>
<span class="text-muted">No need to take off battery just to be 100% sure.</span></p>

        </div>
      </div>
      <h1>Interested? <span class="text-muted text-small">You can help!</span></h1>
        <p>We're currently forming <strong>The Fremantle Porting Task Force</strong> which is going to work on bringing <strong>Maemo&trade; 5</strong> to the <strong class="neo900">Neo900</strong> platform.
       </p>
        <p><a class="btn btn-primary btn-lg btn-big" href="http://talk.maemo.org/showthread.php?t=91142">See the Maemo Talk forum thread &raquo;</a></p>
        <p>Witness the birth of something really unique!</p>
]]></description>
   </item>

 </channel>
</rss>
